Guide to the Marcus Cunliffe papers, 1960-1990 MS0125.UA
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Pamphlets papers, and reprints, 1950-1988; MS0125 Series 8; 5.5 Linear feet (Box 91, Box 92, Box 86, Box 93, Box 85, Box 96, Box 90, Box 89, Box 94, Box 88, Box 95, Box 87)
  - Pamphlets: B - Berthoff, Warner American Literature: Traditions and Talents (1957); Blake, Judith Family Size in the 1960's - A Baffling Fad (1967); Bestor, Arthur History as Verifiable Knowledge: The Logic of Historical Inquiry and Explanation (1971); Bellamy, Edward An Echo of Antietam (1889), undated (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlets: B - Books about Early America: A Selected Bibliography (1970); Butterfield, L.H. The Papers of the Adams Family: Some Accounts of Their History (1957), undated (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets: C - Clark, G.N. Cecil Rhodes and His College (1953); Clough, Wilson Libraries for Liberty (1958); Compton, James Anti-Communism in American Life since the Second World War (1973); Cunliffe, Marcus The Changing Image of George Washington (exhibit catalog) (1989), undated (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets: C - Cobaen, R. England, Ireland, and America (1835); Common Sense by an American (1872); Clough, Wilson O. Poe's "The City in the Sea" Revisited (1967), undated (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets: C - Contasta, David R. Henry Adams and the Decline of the Modern West (1980); Cunliffe, Marcus American Thought (n.d.), undated (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets: C-CH Chamberlain, M.E. The New Imperialism (1970); Christmas Letters to the Fellows (1982), undated (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Pamphlets: CI - "Civil War Newspapers" (facsimiles of front pages), undated (Box 90, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlets: D - Degler, Carl "Remaking American History"; "A Disputation on the Future of Democracy" (1978), undated (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets: D - Donoghue, Denis Emily Dickinson (1969); Davis, David Some Recent Directions in American Cultural History (1968); Davies, Wallace Genealogy: History's Neglected Stepsister (1957); Davies, Wallace The Mexican War Veterans as an Organized Group (1948), undated (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets: D-E - Easum, Chester Benjamin Franklin, an American of the Enlightenment (1956); Ekirch, Arthur American Intellectual History (1963); Emerson Society Quarterly (1966), undated (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets: E - "Eisenhower's America" (1956);"Engraved Portraits of Washington" (1898), undated (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets: F - Fleming, Donald The Centenary of the Origin of Species (1959); Franklin, John Hope The Great Confrontation: The South and the Problem of Change (1972); Fenn, G. Manville Land Ahead or The Irish Immigrant (play) (1877); Fishwick, Marshall Where Do "American Studies" Begin?(1959), undated (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Pamphlets: Farrell, James T. - writings, 1949-1960 (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - Pamphlets: G - Galbraith, J.K. A Beginner's Guide to American Studies (1967); Grenville, J. Great Britain and the Isthmian Canal, 1898-1901 (1955), undated (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlets: G - Gidley, M. Audio-Visual Materials for American Studies (1970); Grattan, Thomas Colley England and the Disrupted States of America (1862); Grant, Douglas Walt Whitman and His English Admirers (1962), undated (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets: G - Greene, Jack P. Historians Analyze the Constitutional Era (1986), undated (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets: H - Hulbert, Archer Butler Washington's Tour of the Ohio and Articles of the Mississippi Company (1908); Henderson, Catalogue of the Henderson Memorial Library of Books on America (1947); Hodson, H.V. The Anatomy of Anglo-American Relations (1962), undated (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets: H - I - Handlin, Oscar The Civil War as Symbol and as Actuality (1961); Holt, W. Stull The Historical Profession in the United States (1963); Hodson, H.V. Problems in Anglo-American Relations (1963); Impeachment and the U.S. Congress (1974), undated (Box 91, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets: H-J - Hampson, Norman History and Fiction: Where does the Difference Lie? (1964); Jones, Howard Mumford Humane Traditions in America: A List of Suggested Readings(1961), undated (Box 91, Folder 6)
  - Pamphlets: I to J - Jarrett, Thomas Recent Fiction by Negroes" (1954); Johnson, Chalmers Comparing Communist Nations (1970); Johnson, Douglass France and the World Beyond (1969), undated (Box 91, Folder 7)
  - Pamphlets: K - Kahn, Sholom J. Whitman's "Black Lucifer": Some Possible Sources (1956); Knowles, David The Historian and Character (1955), undated (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - Pamphlets: K - Kennedy, Emmet Studies on Voltaire and the Eighteenth Century (1981); Kretzoi, Charlotte William Styron: Heritage and Conscience (1971); Kevles, Daniel J. Testing the Army's Intelligence: Psychologists and the Military in World War I (1968), undated (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlets: K-L Kammen, Michael, et al - History and Theory (1972); Vanitas and the Historian's Vocation (1982); Kantor, MacKinlay The Historical Novelist's Obligation to History (1966);Levin, Harry The Modern Humanities in Historical Perspective n.d.; Paradises, Heavenly, and Earthly (1966); The Title as a Literary Genre (1977), undated (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets: L - Levin, Harry The American Voice in English Poetry (1961); Lijphart, Arend Typologies of Democratic Systems (1968); Latimer, John Life of George Washington in Latin Prose (1976), undated (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets: L - Lippman, Walter U.S. Foreign Policy: Shield of the Republic (1943); Loewenberg, Bert Darwinism Comes to America (1941), undated (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets: M - Mann, Arthur British Social Thought and American Reformers of the Progressive Era (1956); Meyerson, Martin The Ethos of the American College Student: Beyond the Protests (1966), undated (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets: M - May, Ernest The Coming of the War, 1917 (1963); McClelland, Donald R. Where Shadows Live: Alice Pike Barney and Her Friends (1978), undated (Box 92, Folder 6)
  - Pamphlets: M - Miller, Perry Thoreau in the Context of International Romanticism (1961); Murrin, John The Myths of Colonial Democracy and Royal Decline in Eighteenth Century America (1965); A More Perfect Union: The Creation of the United States Constitution (1978), undated (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlets: N - Nixon, Richard U.S. Foreign Policy for the 1970's (1973); Nuesse, George C. George Washington and Masonry (1930), undated (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets: Norman W. Caldwell articles from Mid-America on the military, 1956, undated (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets: O - Over Here: An American Studies Journal (1980), undated (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets: P - Pearce, Roy Mass Culture/Popular Culture (1962); Persons, Stow Public Opinion - A Democratic Dilemma (1958), undated (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets: P - Presidential Portraits (1968); Pizer, Donald The Concept of Nature in Frank Norris' "The Octopus" (c.1960); Pierson, George W. The Humanities and Moral Man (1965), undated (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Pamphlets: P - Printed in the Confederacy [book catalog] (c.1985); Prime, Colonel Ralph Earl George Clinton (1902), undated (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Pamphlets: P - Plumb, J.H., New Light on the Tyranny of George III (1978); The Provision of the Federal Benefits for Veterans [Congressional Report] (1955), undated (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlets: R - Ramsey, A.M. Oratory and Literature (1960); Ross, Hugh The Cold War: Containment and its Critics (n.d.), undated (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets: R - Read, Donald Edwardian England (1972); Jamestowne in the Words of Contemporaries (1964), undated (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets: R - Regional American Studies Information Clearinghouse (1980), undated (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets: R - Robinson, LeRoy Various articles on John Howard Lawson (1980's); Rele, J.R. Some Correlations of the Age at Marriage in the United States (1965); Riese, Teut Andreas Vistas of a Continent: Concepts of Nature in America (1979), undated (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets: S-Sch - Schlesinger, Arthur M. Jr. The Constitution and Presidential Leadership (1988); de Seynes, Philippe Prospects for a Future Whole World" (1972); The St. John's Book List: Books That Have Helped Shape Western Civilization, undated (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Pamphlets: Sch-Sh - Shahn, Ben The Museum of Modern Art (1947); Shuttleworth, Alan Two Working Papers in Cultural Studies (1966), undated (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - Pamphlets: S - Snowman, Daniel President Truman's Decision to Drop the First Atomic Bomb (1966); Spratt, H.P. Outline History of Transatlantic Steam Navigation (1950); Strout, Cushing Ego Psychology and the Historian (1968), undated (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Pamphlets: S - Saito, Makato American Studies in Pre-War Japan (1970); Shepperson, George The Free Church and American Slavery (n.d.); Sparks, Jared Letter to Lord Mahon (1852), undated (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Pamphlets: S - Sumner, Charles Alabama Treaty: Speech of Hon. Charles Sumner against its Ratification by the Senate of the United States (1869); Smith, Goldwin England and America (1865); Shafer, Boyd Nationalism: Interpreters and Interpretation (1959), undated (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets: T - Temperly, Howard American Studies in Britain (1966); Tilberg, Frederick Fort Necessity (1954); Tuner, Arlin Nathaniel Hawthorne in American Studies (1964), undated (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Pamphlets: T - Thistlethwaite, Frank Migration from Europe Overseas in the Nineteenth and Twentieth Centuries (1960); Thorp, Margaret Farrand Sarah Orne Jewett (1966); Theodore (exhibit catalog on Teddy Roosevelt (1984), undated (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Pamphlets: W - Washburn, Wilcomb Samuel Eliot Morison, Historian (1979); Exhibition of Portraits of George Washington at the Corcoran Gallery of Art (1932); Whitmarsh, Guy New Perspectives in the Teaching of History (1965); Woodward, C. Vann Equality: America's Deferred Commitment (1958), undated (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Pamphlets: U-W - Walne, Peter A Mystery Resolved: George Washington's Letter to Governor Dinwiddle, 06/10/1754 (1971); Ward, John William Mill, Marx, and Modern Individualism (1959); Washington's Journal, Williamsburg, 1754 (1958), undated (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Pamphlets: V-W - Valuable Autograph Letters and Historical Documents (1909); Whitehead, Alfred North Nature and Life (1980 reprint of 1934 edition); Welland, Dennis Mark Twain's Last Travel Book (1965); Woodard, C. Vann The Future of the Past (1970); Washington Salutes Washington, The President and the State (1989); Why There is no Socialism in the United States, undated (Box 96, Folder 1)
- Illustrations and photographs, 1849-1903; MS0125 Series 9; 1 Linear foot (Box 97, Box 96)
  This series consists of 19th century illustrations and various photographs (photos of Cunliffe can be found in Box 8). The illustrations feature British military leaders such as Lord Roberts and military scenes, taken from magazines of the day. The photos include 19th and 20th century scenes of American cities such as New York, San Francisco, Washington, and Chicago. There are also photo reproductions from illustrations of 19th century wars and political leaders, including scenes from the Revolutionary War, War of 1812, Mexican-American War, and Civil War.
  - Illustrations and photographs, undated (Box 96)
  - Illustrations: Field-Marshal Viscount Wolseley (photomechanical prints), 1901 (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Illustrations: Earl Roberts of Kandaher, Pretoria, and Waterford (photomechanical print), undated (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Illustrations: Lord Roberts, V.C. (photomechanical print), undated (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Illustrations: The Sirdar at Cambridge/Lord Kitchener, (etching), undated (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Illustrations: Days with Celebrites from the Cambridge Jubilee(engraving), 1887 (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Illustrations: Sir Charles Warren (engraving), 1888 (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - Illustrations: Lt. J.R.M. Chard, Lt. G. Bromhead [Heroes of Rorkes' Drift] (engraving), 1879 (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - Illustrations: Sirdar receiving the Freedom of the City (etching), undated (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - Illustrations: Sir Garnet Wolseley and Duke of Cambridge (engraving), 1880 (Box 96, Folder 11)
  - Illustrations: General Gordon, heroic defender of Khartoum (engraving), 1885 (Box 96, Folder 12)
  - Illustrations: Lord Wolseley speech in House of Commons (photomechanical print), 1907 (Box 96, Folder 13)
  - Illustrations: Maj. Gen. A. Hunter, Maj. Gen. H.M. Leslie Rundle, Maj. Gen. B.B.D. Campbell, Col. H.L. Smith-Dorrien (photomechanical print), 1901 (Box 96, Folder 14)
  - Illustrations: How the Peerage has suffered by the war (photomechanical print), 1901 (Box 96, Folder 15)
  - Illustrations: General Redvers Henry Buller (photomechanical print), 1896 (Box 96, Folder 16)
  - Illustrations: Colonel Herbert Plumer, various photos and article, 1900 (Box 96, Folder 17)
  - Illustrations: Colonel Robert G. Kekewich (photomechanical print), 1900 (Box 96, Folder 18)
  - Illustrations: Major-General Lord Methuen, various photos and engravings, 1884-1900 (Box 96, Folder 19)
  - Illustrations: Colonel Lord Albemarle, 2 photos, 1901 (Box 96, Folder 20)
  - Illustrations: London Rifle Brigade, photo and article, 1903 (Box 96, Folder 21)
  - Illustrations: Sir Charles Lyttelton, (photomechanical print), undated (Box 96, Folder 22)
  - Illustrations: The Late General Havelock, (engraving), undated (Box 96, Folder 23)
  - Illustrations: William Henry Wellesley, Earl Cowley (engraving and article), 1887 (Box 96, Folder 24)
  - Illustrations: Luke White, Lord Annaly (engraving and article), 1873 (Box 96, Folder 25)
  - Illustrations: Captain J. Foster (engraving and article), 1887 (Box 96, Folder 26)
  - Illustrations: Major General Mark Wood (engraving and article), 1880 ca. (Box 96, Folder 27)
  - Illustrations: Captain J.E.P. Spicer (engraving and article), 1889 (Box 96, Folder 28)
  - Illustrations: Captain Pritchard-Rayner (engraving and article), 1882 (Box 96, Folder 29)
  - Illustrations: Captain E.W. Park Yates (engraving and article), 1880 (Box 96, Folder 30)
  - Illustrations: Colonel Walrond (engraving), undated (Box 96, Folder 31)
  - Illustrations: Captain T.J. Walker (engraving), undated (Box 96, Folder 32)
  - Illustrations: Colonel Nigel Fitzhardinge Kingscote (engraving and article), 1891 (Box 96, Folder 33)
  - Illustrations: Colonel Henry Tomkinson (engraving and article), 1897 (Box 96, Folder 34)
  - Illustrations: Lt. Colonel Byrne (engraving and article), 1900 ca. (Box 96, Folder 35)
  - Illustrations: Captain Gratrex (photo and article), 1897 (Box 96, Folder 36)
  - Illustrations: Lt. General F. Marshall (engraving and article), 1888 (Box 96, Folder 37)
  - Illustrations: Captain Graham Foster Pigott (engraving and article), 1890 (Box 96, Folder 38)
  - Illustrations: Major Robert M. Poore (engraving and article), 1899 (Box 96, Folder 39)
  - Illustrations: Hugh Richard Dawnay, Viscount Downe (engraving and article), 1895 (Box 96, Folder 40)
  - Illustrations: General William Fenwick Williams (engraving and article), 1890 ca. (Box 96, Folder 41)
  - Illustrations: Major General William Fenwick Williams (engraving and articles), 1856 (Box 96, Folder 42)
  - Illustrations: General Frederick Haines (engraving and article), 1880 (Box 96, Folder 43)
  - Illustrations: General Hugh Halkett (engraving and article), 1863 (Box 96, Folder 44)
  - Illustrations: Lt. Colonel E.W. Pakenham (engraving and article), 1855 (Box 96, Folder 45)
  - Illustrations: Viscount Stratford de Redcliffe (engravings), 1853-1876 (Box 96, Folder 46)
  - Illustrations: Lord Robert's family (photos and article), 1901 (Box 96, Folder 47)
  - Illustrations: Funeral procession of the Duchess of Cambridge (engraving), 1889 (Box 96, Folder 48)
  - Illustrations: "A Future Commander-in-Chief" (color illustration), undated (Box 96, Folder 49)
  - Illustrations: Duke of Connaught (photo, illustration, and article), undated (Box 96, Folder 50)
  - Illustrations: Lord Roberts and his Daughters at Pretoria (photomechanical print), 1900 (Box 96, Folder 51)
  - Illustrations: Lord Roberts on horseback and his son (photomechanical print), undated (Box 96, Folder 52)
  - Illustrations: "Bobs" (Lord Roberts) (color illustration), 1889 (Box 96, Folder 53)
  - Illustrations: Field Marshall Lord Roberts (photomechanical print), 1900 (Box 96, Folder 54)
  - Illustrations: "Duke of Cambridge's Gallop" (music sheets), undated (Box 96, Folder 55)
  - Illustrations: Lord Roberts, Commander-in-Chief in South Africa (color illustration), 1900 ca. (Box 96, Folder 56)
  - Illustrations: The Duke of Cambridge (engravings and article), 1900 ca. (Box 96, Folder 57)
  - Illustrations: Jubilee of F.M. the Duke of Cambridge's Army Service (engravings), 1883 (Box 96, Folder 58)
  - Illustrations: Major General Frederick Roberts (engraving and article), 1881 (Box 96, Folder 59)
  - Illustrations: Field Marshal Earl Roberts (photomechanical print), undated (Box 96, Folder 60)
  - Illustrations: Duke of Cambridge (color illustration), 1889 (Box 96, Folder 61)
  - Illustrations: "The Finishing Blow in Afghanistan: Donald Stewarts's Great Victory at Ghuznee," (engravings), 1880 (Box 96, Folder 62)
  - Illustrations: General Donald Stewart (engraving), 1885 (Box 96, Folder 63)
  - Illustrations: "Redan" Massy (engraving and articles), 1879 (Box 96, Folder 64)
  - Illustrations: Lt. General Sir Walter Raleigh Gilbert (engravings and article), 1853 (Box 96, Folder 65)
  - Illustrations: Family tree of Barons Chelmsford and article, undated (Box 96, Folder 66)
  - Illustrations: Lord Chelmsford (engraving and color illustration), 1858-1881 (Box 96, Folder 67)
  - Illustrations: Major General Henry Havelock (engravings and articles), 1857-1858 (Box 96, Folder 68)
  - Illustrations: Brigadier General Cureton (engraving), 1849 (Box 96, Folder 69)
  - Illustrations: Field Marshal Lord Clyde (engravings), 1863 (Box 96, Folder 70)
  - Illustrations: Constantine Henry Phipps, Marquis of Normanby (engraving), 1863 (Box 96, Folder 71)
  - Illustrations: Major General Alexander Murray Tulloch (engraving and article), 1864 (Box 96, Folder 72)
  - Illustrations: Viscount Chewton (engraving), 1854 (Box 96, Folder 73)
  - Illustrations: General John Fox Burgoyne (engraving), 1866 (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - Illustrations: Major General Henry William Barnard (engraving), 1858 (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Illustrations: Lord Napier of Magdala (engraving), 1878 (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - Illustrations: British Home Military and Volunteer Leaders (engraving), 1884 (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - Illustrations: Lord Kitchener of Khartoum (engraving and color illustration and articles), 1884-1899 (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - Illustrations: Lord Wolseley (color illustration), 1874 (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - Illustrations: General Lord Wolseley in Egypt (engravings), 1884 (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - Illustrations: "Some of the Officers Whom the King Delights to Honour,", 1890 ca. (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - Illustrations: Lt. General Sir Henry Daly (engraving), 1887 (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - Illustrations: Engravings - Presidents of the United States (Washington, Jackson. Lincoln, Johnson), 1876 (Box 97, Folder 10)
  - Illustrations: Engraving - Washington's Reception at Trenton, 1887 (Box 97, Folder 11)
  - Illustrations: Engraving photocopy - Pilot's Certificate for a steamboat, 1859 (Box 97, Folder 12)
  - Photographs and Slides: Photos and negatives - New York (19th and early 20th centuries), undated (Box 97, Folder 13)
  - Photographs and Slides: Photos and negatives - San Francisco (19th and early 20th centuries), undated (Box 97, Folder 14)
  - Photographs and Slides: Photos and negatives - Washington, D.C. (19th and early 20th centuries), undated (Box 97, Folder 15)
  - Photographs and Slides: Photos and negatives - Chicago (19th and early 20th centuries), undated (Box 97, Folder 16)
  - Photographs and Slides: Photos and negatives - Miscellaneous cities (19th and early 20th centuries), undated (Box 97, Folder 17)
  - Photographs and Slides: Photo reproductions of illustrations - Revolutionary War, undated (Box 97, Folder 18)
  - Photographs and Slides: Photo reproductions of illustrations - War of 1812, undated (Box 97, Folder 19)
  - Photographs and Slides: Photo reproductions of illustrations -- Mexican-American War, undated (Box 97, Folder 20)
  - Photographs and Slides: Photo reproductions of illustrations -- 1830's and 1840's, undated (Box 97, Folder 21)
  - Photographs and Slides: Photo reproductions of illustrations -- 1850's, undated (Box 97, Folder 22)
  - Photographs and Slides: Photo reproductions of illustrations - Civil War, undated (Box 97, Folder 23)
  - Photographs and Slides: Photo reproductions of illustrations - Miscellaneous war scenes, undated (Box 97, Folder 24)
  - Photographs and Slides: Photo reproductions of illustrations - Political Leaders, 19th century, undated (Box 97, Folder 25)
  - Photographs and Slides: Photo reproductions of illustrations - 19th century song and military march music books, undated (Box 97, Folder 26)
  - Photographs and Slides: Photograph - Palermo Villa Trabia garden and fountain, 1987; and miscellaneous caricature, undated (Box 97, Folder 27)
  - Photographs and Slides: Slides -- Imaginary Wars (see also Box 46), undated (Box 97, Folder 28)
  - Photographs and Slides: Slides - Abraham Lincoln and George Washington (see also Box 46 and 55), undated (Box 97, Folder 29)
  - Napolon Bonaparte ('The valley of the shadow of death') hand-colored etching and aquatint, 1808 (Box 104, Folder 1)
  - Overthrow of the Republican-Babel, hand-coloured etching, 1809 (Box 104, Folder 2)
    Biographical / Historical
    By James Gillray, published by Hannah Humphrey
  - Blarney, or a Hibernian Addrejs on the Coronation - a specimen of an Irish Oration for the Edification of the English Nation, hand colored ethching (Box 104, Folder 3)
  - The Morning after Marriage-or- A scene on the Continent, hand colored etching, 1788 (Box 104)
- Oversize materials, 1872-1988; MS0125 Series 10; 1 Linear foot
  This series consists of large 19th century illustrations, a facsimile of the U.S. Constitution, and a certificate signed by President Bill Clinton (then governor of Arkansas) which was presented to Cunliffe in 1988.
  - Calendar - Two Hundred Years of German-American Relations, 1976 (Oversize 98, Folder 1)
  - Certificate - Arkansas Traveler award given to Cunliffe (signed by Governor Bill Clinton), 05/21/1988 (Oversize 98, Folder 2)
  - Charters of Freedom - Declaration of Independence, Constitution, Bill of Rights, 1952 (Oversize 98, Folder 3)
  - The Constitution of the United States - A Facsimile, 1935 (Oversize 98, Folder 4)
  - Engraving - General Isaac Gascoyne, undated (Oversize 98, Folder 5)
  - Engraving - Little Mac Trying to Dig His Way to the White House, undated (Oversize 98, Folder 6)
  - Engraving - Splitting the Party, 1872 (Oversize 98, Folder 7)
  - Engraving and photograph - "The debilitated situation of a monarchical government when puffed up...The flourishing of a well formed industrious republic,", 1870 ca. (Oversize 98, Folder 8)
  - Engraving -- "A Pilgrimage -- New Zealander,", 1872 (Oversize 98, Folder 9)
  - Life magazine article- "The American Revolution: The Story as it really Happened,", 07/03/1950 (Oversize 98, Folder 10)
  - Life magazine - "All the President's Children,", 11/1984 (Oversize 98, Folder 11)
  - Photograph - Fellows and Staff of the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences (including Cunliffe), 09/19/1957 (Oversize 98, Folder 12)
  - Photograph - The Grand Review at Camp Massachusetts, 1859 (Oversize 98, Folder 13)
  - Photograph - H.R.H. The Duke of Connaught, undated (Oversize 98, Folder 14)